<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on matkv.dev</title><link>https://matkv.dev/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on matkv.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>test</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 18:17:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matkv.dev/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trying out local LLMs</title><link>https://matkv.dev/trying-out-local-llms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 18:17:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.dev/trying-out-local-llms/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying out local LLMs for the first time this weekend. I installed &lt;a href="https://ollama.com/">Ollama&lt;/a> locally on Windows and then downloaded two models just to play around with them: Deepseek R1 &amp;amp; LLama 2 Uncensored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote a little &lt;a href="https://wiki.matkv.dev/local-llms">tutorial&lt;/a> for myself that lets me download Ollama &amp;amp; the models to a different drive than the default location because they take up quite a bit of storage space. I also think it&amp;rsquo;s wild that you basically need as much free &lt;strong>RAM&lt;/strong> as the &lt;strong>size of the model&lt;/strong> in order to run it. So for the models with huge amounts of parameters you need some pretty insane setups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trying out Tailscale</title><link>https://matkv.dev/trying-out-tailscale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:51:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.dev/trying-out-tailscale/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in trying out &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/">Tailscale&lt;/a> recently - it is a tool that allows you to set up a secure network between your personal devices. This allows you to access them from anywhere as if they are on the same local network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the main usecases for me would be to be able to access my dev projects on my phone while I&amp;rsquo;m working on them on my Windows desktop or within WSL Arch Linux. That way I can test this website or other web based projects on my phone without having to actually publish them anywhere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Obsidian / Teuxdeux / Omnivore setup</title><link>https://matkv.dev/my-obsidian-teuxdeux-omnivore-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.dev/my-obsidian-teuxdeux-omnivore-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>A quick overview of what I&amp;rsquo;m using as my personal knowledge base and to-do list.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trying out Obsidian</title><link>https://matkv.dev/trying-out-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 20:46:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.dev/trying-out-obsidian/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in personal knowledge base systems recently. After reading about several different ones, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to give &lt;strong>Obsidian&lt;/strong> a shot &amp;amp; try moving all my existing notes there &amp;amp; set up an Obsidian vault from scratch.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>