<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on matkv.dev</title><link>https://matkv.dev/library/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on matkv.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matkv.dev/library/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Girl Who Kicked the Hornet's Nest (Millennium, #3)</title><link/><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid/><description/></item><item><title>The Girl With the Dragon Tattoo</title><link/><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid/><description>&lt;p&gt;Wanted a change of pace so I read a thriller / crime novel for the first time in quite a while. The book started pretty action-packed but then slowed down in the first third and lost me for a couple of weeks which means that it took me a while to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After giving it another shot it managed to hook me and the conclusion to the plot lines was satisfying but felt a little bit rushed. But the main two characters are really likable even if they&amp;rsquo;re a bit cliche. Also everyone seems to sleep with everyone in this book, lol.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>All Systems Red (The Murderbot Diaries 1)</title><link/><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid/><description>&lt;p&gt;This book is written from the perspective of a security bot (in a science fiction setting) which managed to become independent. The book follows its thoughts now that it has to deal with social awkwardness, its pessimistic worldview and the human clients on whose mission it has to protect them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murderbot has such a fun personality, constantly complaining about not being able to spend its time watching entertainment shows and trying avoiding any interaction with humans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>1984</title><link/><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid/><description>&lt;p&gt;I personally don&amp;rsquo;t find Orwell&amp;rsquo;s writing to be very engaging but overall I liked the book; definitely worth reading it for the references and general impact on popular culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Stand</title><link/><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid/><description/></item></channel></rss>