<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on matkv</title><link>https://matkv.github.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on matkv</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://matkv.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chess openings</title><link>https://matkv.github.io/notes/chess-openings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.github.io/notes/chess-openings/</guid><description>Tactical vs. Positional openings Link to the Google Presentation for an overview of chess openings that I found on Reddit.
To-Do: look up if I can embed lichess games directly here on the site using this.
Tactical opening Usually sharp &amp;amp; typically open position Often many pawns have been traded off Gambit openings (willingly sacrificing material to gain lead in development) Tends to require more theory Gambits are good for players that love to sacrifice material &amp;amp; work well against unprepared players, especially in speed chess (blitz, bullet) Positional opening Often closed position Pawns blocking each other in the center Gradual improvement by maneuvering Depriving opponents pieces of active squares, preparing pawn breaks Play tends to be slow paced, knowledge of general strategy is more important than memorizing theory System based vs.</description></item><item><title>Programming project ideas</title><link>https://matkv.github.io/notes/programming-project-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.github.io/notes/programming-project-ideas/</guid><description>Apart from building this website, I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to find a programming project that I am really passionate about. This page is supposed to help me to find ideas for some fun &amp;amp; useful projects!
Lichess stats - a cli tool that shows statistics and basic information about any player on Lichess. Maybe using tui to build the UI in the command line &amp;amp; communicating with the Lichess API to fetch the data.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi project ideas</title><link>https://matkv.github.io/notes/raspberry-pi-project-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.github.io/notes/raspberry-pi-project-ideas/</guid><description> mirror of my GitHub profile with regularly scheduled backups or just a local git server a syncthing device with local harddrive Kodi / Plex client (but I wouldn’t really be able to watch 4K content because the Raspberry probably won&amp;rsquo;t be powerful enough to play it without stuttering)</description></item><item><title>Website improvements</title><link>https://matkv.github.io/notes/website-improvements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matkv.github.io/notes/website-improvements/</guid><description>Some ideas for content that I want to put on this website:
Done a personal blog page with information about myself a reading list &amp;amp; place to review books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, basically an online library / bookshelf, maybe a way to replace my Goodreads account programming side projects a custom bookmarks page for websites and links I commonly use (maybe just one big html table) page for random notes To-Do a digital cv - either just hosting a PDF or writing some custom css to format everything nicely changelog for this website maybe a page about this website in general and why I created it / why I&amp;rsquo;m using it maybe switch the domain to &amp;ldquo;matkv.</description></item></channel></rss>